Hi, dear students. I hope you're all doing well.
Welcome to our first class and also welcome
to INHA University back.
And hopefully, this will be your final year here, right?
And let's start our class today, which is a distinguished lecture in social science and arts.
Okay, just a minute.
Okay, hopefully my screen is visible to you guys.
So as mentioned, our subject this semester is a distinguished lecture in social science and
arts. And today we'll have some basic information, some general information about our
subject. So that since this
is not a required subject, right?
This is an elective subject.
So that those of you who are
thinking still about it, whether to continue or to drop it,
you'll have a much better idea
after this lecture.
Today, we'll talk about mainly two points.
First of all, we'll talk about the syllabus
or general information about our
subject. Secondly, in the second part of our today's lecture, we'll talk about the topic, Chapter
1. I'll let you know more information later.
Also, I mean, to begin with, we guys are already familiar, right?
So, therefore, I didn't put details about myself.
So, as you can see, my name is Bobby Mbratov, and I have been working at IoT since 2015,
right? I think I told you about this information
on our last year's subject, right?
And
also, later on, I went to my PhD, and since 2015,
I came back and have been working here at Inha University in Tashkent.
Since last year, I transferred to a faculty position.
Okay, then let's continue.
Let's talk about our subject.
So to begin with, I like the name of our subject.
So what do you guys think?
What are social sciences, humanities and arts?
Because usually when we talk about these subjects, whether it's in Uzbek, or some other
languages, right? We usually mix them, right?
Social science and humanities.
Or we can say that
like in the Russian or in Uzbek, right?
Like for example, right?
We kind of usually mix them.
But can you guys differentiate them?
So you can pause this video and think about it.
I'll continue.
So
let's begin from with the social science, okay?
So the main difference between the social science and humanities, like you guys see,
social science is a subject that studies the interactions
or kind of communications between humans, okay?
It's kind of, it studies the
individuals, communities, societies and how they behave or how they interact
within these communities, within this society, right?
and how they impact environment, for example, right?
And therefore, the subjects, as you can see, such as sociology, right?
Economics or
anthropology or politics, right?
Or psychology. These are the subjects that study the human behavior, right?
So how humans interact with each other, right?
And whereas the humanities is also about humans, however, they do not study the kind
of interaction between humans, but they study the activities of humans, okay,
of their kind of history, culture, language, right, like you can see the subjects like literature,
for example, right, on how
humans perform, right, on what kind of activities humans do, and also the arts and the language,
right, these are the kind of activities of people, right, and the
Arts is also part of humanities, as you guys can see.
It's a kind of a mode of expression, right?
That use kind of a skill or imagination, right?
In the creation of a certain kind of products, right?
And the next logical question is, why do we need these subjects?
Or more importantly, I mean, you guys may be asking yourselves and me, why do you guys need
this subject? So you can pause this video and kind of reflect about it.
Okay, so this will be the question for you guys to ponder and to think about it, okay?
And just let me give my brief ideas about it.
So we can start from course description, right?
So the main of this course is kind of to introduce you guys because you guys are studying in
kind of
technology field, right?
In computer science or information and communication engineering, right?
Where you mainly study some kind of hard subjects, right?
Maybe some sciences, right?
Like kind of pure sciences, maybe, right?
Maybe I'm making a mistake, but like you're studying physics and math, right?
And some applied subjects or engineering subjects, right?
And whereas you have a very kind of few opportunities to study the social science
and humanities, right? So therefore, the aim of this subject is to introduce you guys to some
of the
important or some of the interesting topics in this field, and also to help you guys to develop
some of the critical thinking skills and abilities, okay?
And we can also
engage in these kind of discussions, and hopefully we'll have also debates, okay?
So later on, I'll give you information.
And hopefully,
these skills will help you guys to broaden your horizons beyond
your
technical field. Because we know, I think last year in
engineering communications or business communications class, I mentioned about this, today
we're living in a very kind of strange period, right?
Like, especially in the last three, four years, right?
With the introduction of these large language models, right?
Now they kind of became very common, right?
We're kind of living in a very strange period, right?
Where kind of things are blurred, everything is messy, and especially the guys like you guys,
the young people, you may be worried about your future, right?
Because of this
strange tools, right? And now, I mean, even the universities, even the kind of leaders,
and even the parents, right?
They may be worried, right?
I mean, what's going on? What's waiting us in the future?
And therefore, I mean, taking into consideration this kind of macro environment, right?
So I believe that this course is a kind of right on time for you guys, so that in the time
of this JNI, where kind of most of the kind of
some skills, right? Some hard skills even
they can be kind of received through the means of this internet or through the means of these
generative tools, right?
So the logical question many of us may be asking ourselves, so what is the role of human, right?
What is our role, right? And what we'll be doing kind of to fulfill kind of our
dreams or to kind of to have just life
satisfaction, right? Because usually the humans were kind of
going to job or working on some tasks for a long period of time, right?
And this would bring them some kind of satisfaction, right?
And now, because of these tools, I mean, now we still, I think we're in a period of some kind
of
transition, right? So maybe within three, four years or five years, I think you will, we may
have much more clearance.
So to make it short, I mean, I think in this age and with these tools, I think
similar subjects, right, would help you guys, especially to
kind of develop some of the soft skills, some of the critical skills and some of the kind of
people skills and social skills, right?
that may not be kind of imitated or that may not be assisted with the use of AI
tools. And this can hopefully differentiate you guys from many other young people in
the field or in the market, okay?
Okay, here are some of the topics, which is our schedule
for this semester. So as you can see,
it's divided mainly into two themes, right?
So until midterm, we'll be studying the topics related to critical thinking.
So I found a book later on, I will introduce you.
Secondly, I mean, right after the midterm, the second part of our semester will be devoted
more on this social science aspect.
So hopefully we'll have three or four lectures, kind of seminars or
kind of
distinguished lectures, let's say.
Okay, so I didn't decide on exact topics yet, but I'm still thinking and hopefully I'll find
some topics which can be interesting
to have some broader understanding or broader kind of interest on this area, okay?
And also which would help also to develop physical thinking skills and also
prepare you guys for the last part of our semester, which is about debates, right?
So here I highlighted, right, in bold.
So since
I mean, even though this subject is online, but because of what I have just talked here, right,
because of these AI tools and other things, so we don't want to rely on them, right?
So I really want to warn you guys, right?
So
use this course,
kind of an opportunity to
use your own brain, to develop your own thinking skills, okay?
Because probably this your final year and maybe kind of one of the
last periods of your lifetime where you will have such opportunity right because later on when
you go to work when you go to kind of a real life right maybe at home you'll be busy with your
family at work maybe you just have to follow the orders you just have to be busy with this
coding and or white coding how are they they're telling now right or some other kind of maybe
management or work right i mean depending on profession you're choosing but you may
have a very few time kind of to just sit and reflect or think critically or write
something that's kind of of your own interest or have some reading of the topics which is kind
of in your own interest area, right?
So therefore, in order to kind of prepare your mind for this career and for this future kind
of hopefully these kind of opportunities, right?
And let's use this semester, this year, and this class specifically to exercise our own
judgment, our own brain, and our own
skills, okay? Because this will be the thing that will differentiate you guys from
thousands or from millions of other young people, okay?
So therefore, as you can see, so we have an offline midterm exam but they will not have a final
exam instead. So as you can see in the last month, we will be having debates and these
debates will be group work.
So also, I mean,
I didn't decide on the
topics of the debates, but as you can see, it will be offline and since
I mean, during the week, I mean, you'll be all already having your own other classes and maybe
work commitments. So I'm planning to make it on Saturdays, okay?
So only the groups which will be having
kind of
presentations or debates on that day, on that week, will have to come, okay?
So,
and the rest will be coming on the next week, okay?
And
we'll know, I mean, about more details maybe right after,
the retake and drop period, okay?
Maybe right after I know how many students are staying or how many students are taking this
class. And then I can kind of write you guys or inform you guys about more details of these
debates, okay? About the topics, about the group format, and about the timing, okay?
But the schedule, as you see, it will be on Saturdays.
So you can start planning from now, okay?
And this is some information about grading.
So as you can see, It's very simple, right?
Just four items. So attendance, just watching these lectures, online lectures and videos.
And we'll be having some quizzes, okay?
Related to lecture materials.
And then midterm exam, as I said, 30%.
And then lastly, a group project, which is a debate, okay?
And
for those, I mean, who are kind of hoping to barely
pass this subject, so you can see, The pass mark will be 40%, okay, of a total grade.
And
also we have university policy, right?
You will have an automatic fail for missing 25% of classes, which means
that the fourth
miss will already be F, okay?
So you can maximum miss three
video lectures.
And
also since this is an online class and this attendance will be counted based on watching all
these online lectures. So there is no excuse
for missing, okay? Maybe you may, God forbid, you may become sick or maybe
hopefully some of you guys may have some kind of
conferences or some competitions in Shanghai, in Dubai, in Europe, for example, right?
Like last year, some of the guys had But still,
thanks God, we have internet everywhere now, right?
And you can still access them.
And this E-Class kind of is a South Korean system, which means it works in many parts of the
world, hopefully. So therefore, there is no excuse for missing these online classes.
And I think this pass mark of 40% is a kind of a fair deal, right?
If you look to the great items, I think this is a, Um, this is not difficult to achieve.
And this is information about communication.
Uh, so, uh, my office, uh, has moved, uh, just, uh, this summer I moved to be, uh,
for, uh,
was you, uh, be, uh, for 10.
It's just on the building on the left side, uh, just, uh, uh, next to, uh, the professor I
was seeing this room. Okay.
Right after his room is in my office.
And the office hours will be announced soon to you guys because the academic affairs in the
first week, they may be changing or doing some updates on timetable, right?
And, but still, I mean, since this is online class in the meantime,
you can use the following means such as you can use eClass message.
I think you guys already know, right?
From last year or my email or through your
printer, right? And also this semester I'm having teaching assistant, hopefully.
His name is Ferda Sabirov.
And as you can see, his email.
So he will be also helping me sometimes.
So in case if you cannot reach me through these three means, you can also use his email also.
And what about Telegram and LinkedIn?
Do you guys think you can use it to reach me?
Well, you guys may think
that you can use it.
But I don't accept. I think some of you may already know about it, right?
Because this is something personal, right?
And since there are many students, and even in Telegram, I have many other, my own contacts
from universities, from three universities, from families and other contacts, right?
I don't want to mix. And, you know, also for you guys, sometimes, let's say you message me
from Telegram
in the evening, and I'm at that time at home, and I just meet...
miss your message right on the weekend right so therefore and let's be professional and don't
message me from these accounts okay just use the official channels okay and however
right after we finish
the course and hopefully maybe the next semester we may have another course maybe right after
when you graduate hopefully we will become friends right And then you can use any means to
reach me if you need any help for anything.
I mean, I'm always, I will be glad to help you guys.
Okay.
So I think this was all for the first part of our lecture.
Let's have a
break here and I'll see you guys in the second part of our lecture.